# **Nick Vorobiov**

Expert in growing IT businesses by bringing new clients, launching new products/services, expanding into new markets, and building sales and marketing systems

linkedin.com/in/nickvorobiov me@nickvorobiov.com +38 (063) 764-5668 skype: nickvorobiov Lviv, Ukraine

# **Summary**

19 years of hands-on B2B sales experience

17 years of experience in planning, budgeting, building, managing and scaling full cycle of sales

13 years of IT sales experience (software, custom development, digital services)

10 years of startup experience

# **Experience**

#### 2020 - Present: Head of Business Development at Vector Software

Responsible for building commercial — marketing, business development, engagement and sales — processes, building and managing commercial teams

Responsible for personal sales to key clients — discussing software needs, presenting development solutions, closing deals

Responsible for developing service offerings, presentation decks and marketing materials Responsible for bringing sales partners and developing partnerships

#### 2018 – 2021: Sales Growth Consultant for IT companies

Helped several IT companies in CIS and Europe to realize their growth ambitions

Designed sales growth strategies, plans and budgets, lead and supervised plan implementation

Developed and refined ideal customer profiles, expanded sales to new markets and new regions

Developed product and service offerings, launched sales of new products and services

Audited and updated existing marketing and sales processes

Built marketing, business development, sales and partnership departments

Conducted key negotiations personally, brought key clients and sales partners

## 2016 – 2019: Founder at a digital marketing company

Developed product offerings, marketing materials, sales and production processes Hired and managed a sales team of 5 and a production team of 30 digital marketers Built over 300 automated sales funnels, launched over 1000 ad campaigns

#### 2009 – 2016: Founder at a training and coaching company

Created training centers in 26 cities of Germany, Czech Republic, Ukraine and Russia Built and managed a sales department of 70 representatives

Presented in front of online and offline audiences of up to 1200 participants

Co-created and hosted 3 television reality shows

#### 2004 – 2010: Head of Sales and Partnerships at a software company

Documented and optimized the sales process
Expanded the sales team to 15 representatives
Found and signed several key sales partners
Created a sales and support office in a new city from scratch
Launched 3 new products and several new markets
Grew company sales up to 4x / year
Brought contracts up to \$1M

#### 2002 – 2004: Engagement manager at a software company

Supported the sales team in understanding clients' software development needs Documented business processes and requirements

Designed architecture solutions, wrote and presented proposals, closed deals

Managed project handover to development department after signing a contract

#### **Education**

#### 2005: Master of Commercial Logistics

St. Petersburg State University of Economics and Finance, Russia Faculty of Commerce and Marketing

### 2001: Microsoft Certified Systems Engineer

#### 2000: Financial and business mathematics

1 year study in the Technical University of Munich, Germany

#### **Skills**

Programming — Python, JavaScript, PHP, SQL

Languages — proficient in English and Russian, good in Ukrainian, beginner in Norwegian and German

Personal qualities — responsible, result-oriented, flexible, charismatic